<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips on OmicX</title>
    <link>https://omicx.cc/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tips on OmicX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 15:54:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omicx.cc/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tips: Pavian Load Large Data</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2021-03-15-tips-pavian-load-large-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 15:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2021-03-15-tips-pavian-load-large-data/</guid>
      <description>Pavian is a interactive browser application for analyzing and visualization metagenomics classification results from classifiers such as Kraken, Centrifuge and MetaPhlAn. Here are a few tips for Pavian to work with large data.
1. Error: Maximum upload size exceeded E.g., Maximum upload 50M files for Pavian, simple input:
pavian::runApp(port=5000, maxUploadSize=50*1024^2) # Or pavian::runApp(port=5000, maxUploadSize=&amp;#34;50M&amp;#34;)  Besides M (megabyte), B (byte), K (kilobyte) and G (gigabyte) also supported. This option is defined in the script runApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create pdf file for huge phylogenetic tree</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-06-22-create-pdf-files-for-huge-phylogenetic-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-06-22-create-pdf-files-for-huge-phylogenetic-tree/</guid>
      <description>Viewing and annotation of a huge phylogenetic tree, especially with hundreds or even thousamds taxa, is always a problem. This post provides a method to split a phylogenetic tree into multiple pages of a PDF file by pdfposter.
1. Install pdfposter There are several ways to install this utility.
1.1 Install via OS package manager sudo apt-get install pdfposter 1.2 Install via pip   Note: It depends Pythonn 3.x</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Open Source Pymol in Windows by Conda</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-05-26-install-pymol-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 21:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-05-26-install-pymol-windows/</guid>
      <description>Since PyMOL 2.x released, there were no binary installer avaliable for Windows.
PyMOL Wiki provides the way to install open source PyMOL in Windows under Python 2.7.
This post provided the method to install PyMOL 2.x by conda (Anaconda or Minoconda) in Windows.
1. Install Conda Download Anaconda or Miniconda and install it.
 Note: Although PyMOL Wiki introduced PyMOL for Python 2.7 only, there are also pre-compiled PyMOL distribution for Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BEAST Tips</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2018-11-16-beast-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 12:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2018-11-16-beast-tips/</guid>
      <description>BEAST (and BEAST 2, of course) is widely uesed for phylogenetic inference. But it is quite complicated. This post represents some useful tips while using BEAST.
1. Install beagle-lib Beagle-lib accelerates Bayesian and Maximun Likelihood phylogenetic software amazingly. Especially the beagle-lib v3.x improves 20-50% than version 2.x.
1.1 Compile beagle-lib without CUDA and OpenCL Although CUDA and OpenCL improves BEAST computing significantly, how to install beagle-lib without an Nvidia GPU card?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
