<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UShER on OmicX</title>
    <link>https://omicx.cc/tags/usher/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UShER on OmicX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 16:39:19 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omicx.cc/tags/usher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create Phylogenetic Tree of SARS CoV 2 by UShER</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2022-11-22-create-phylogenetic-tree-of-sars-cov-2-by-usher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 16:39:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2022-11-22-create-phylogenetic-tree-of-sars-cov-2-by-usher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are nearly 14 million viral genome sequences right now in the GISAID EpiCoV ™ database. It is not likely  to infer the phylogenetic relationships for such a huge dataset by traditional maximum likelyhood or Bayesian methods in a shor time period. The UShER package was developed to generate ultra-large phylogenetic tree of SARS-CoV-2 genomes. The algorithm of the UShER program is to place new samples onto an existing phylogeny using maximum parsimony method. It is able to place given SARS-CoV-2 genome sequences into the GISAID global phylogeny in a couple of hours.  This program is particularly helpful in understanding the relationships of newly sequenced SARS-CoV-2 genomes with each other and with previously sequenced genomes in a global phylogeny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UShER package is composed by four programs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;UShER&lt;/code&gt;: a program that rapidly places new samples onto an existing phylogeny using maximum parsimony.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;matUtils&lt;/code&gt;:  a toolkit for querying, interpreting and manipulating the mutation-annotated trees (MATs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;matOptimize&lt;/code&gt;:  a program to rapidly and effectively optimize a mutation-annotated tree (MAT) for parsimony using subtree pruning and regrafting (SPR) moves within a user-defined radius.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;RIPPLES&lt;/code&gt;: a program that uses a phylogenomic technique to rapidly and sensitively detect recombinant nodes and their ancestors in a mutation-annotated tree (MAT).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The taxoniumtools and &lt;a href=&#34;https://taxonium.org/&#34;&gt;Taxonium website&lt;/a&gt; are used to display the MAT generated by UShER.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
