<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on OmicX</title>
    <link>https://omicx.cc/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on OmicX</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:30:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omicx.cc/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install beagle-lib for NVidia Tesla V100 on Debian buster</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2021-04-09-install-beagle-lib-for-nvidia-tesla-v100-on-debian-buster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 15:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2021-04-09-install-beagle-lib-for-nvidia-tesla-v100-on-debian-buster/</guid>
      <description>BEAGLE-LIB is a high-performance library to accelerate the calculations of Bayesian and Maximun Likelihood phylogenetics analyses. The latest version of beagle-lib was released on Dec 4, 2018.
When compiled for NVidia Tesla V100 on Debian buster 10.9, an error was encountered:
nvcc fatal : Value &amp;#39;compute_30&amp;#39; is not defined for option &amp;#39;gpu-architecture&amp;#39; 1. Install NVidia driver and CUDA toolkit Firstly, append this line in /etc/apt/sources.list
deb http://deb.debian.org/debian buster-backports main contrib non-free Then, install:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips: Pavian Load Large Data</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2021-03-15-tips-pavian-load-large-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 15:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2021-03-15-tips-pavian-load-large-data/</guid>
      <description>Pavian is a interactive browser application for analyzing and visualization metagenomics classification results from classifiers such as Kraken, Centrifuge and MetaPhlAn. Here are a few tips for Pavian to work with large data.
1. Error: Maximum upload size exceeded E.g., Maximum upload 50M files for Pavian, simple input:
pavian::runApp(port=5000, maxUploadSize=50*1024^2) # Or pavian::runApp(port=5000, maxUploadSize=&amp;#34;50M&amp;#34;)  Besides M (megabyte), B (byte), K (kilobyte) and G (gigabyte) also supported. This option is defined in the script runApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install R and RStudio server in Debian</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2021-02-22-install-r-and-rstudio-server-in-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2021-02-22-install-r-and-rstudio-server-in-debian/</guid>
      <description>This post introduces how to complie latest R for RStidio, and install RStudio Server in a Debian host.
1. Compile and Install R for RStudio Install build dependencies: $ sudo apt update $ sudo apt build-dep r-base Install optional packages: The automatically tuned linear algebra software:
$ sudo apt install libatlas3-base Or the multi-threaded OpenBlas library:
$ sudo apt install libopenblas-base Download R source Download R source from: https://cran.rstudio.com/src/base/R-4/
The latest R source is R-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install hdf5r package in R 4.0.2</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2020-10-20-install-hdf5r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 15:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2020-10-20-install-hdf5r-package/</guid>
      <description>While installing the R package &amp;ldquo;hdf5r&amp;rdquo; version 1.3.3, I encountered the error:
fatal error: hdf5.h: No such file or directory #include &amp;lt;hdf5.h&amp;gt; ^~~~~~~~ compilation terminated. My OS is Debian buster/10.6, and the package &amp;ldquo;libhdf5-dev&amp;rdquo; has been installed. It looks R cannot find the path of hdf5 header and library files.
It has been resolved by:
1. Export environment variables for header files export C_INCLUDE_PATH=/usr/include/hdf5/serial/:$C_INCLUDE_PATH export CPLUS_INCLUDE_PATH=/usr/include/hdf5/serial/:$CPLUS_INCLUDE_PATH 2. Create symbolic links for library files cd /usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/ sudo ln -s libhdf5_hl_cpp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create pdf file for huge phylogenetic tree</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-06-22-create-pdf-files-for-huge-phylogenetic-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 21:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-06-22-create-pdf-files-for-huge-phylogenetic-tree/</guid>
      <description>Viewing and annotation of a huge phylogenetic tree, especially with hundreds or even thousamds taxa, is always a problem. This post provides a method to split a phylogenetic tree into multiple pages of a PDF file by pdfposter.
1. Install pdfposter There are several ways to install this utility.
1.1 Install via OS package manager sudo apt-get install pdfposter 1.2 Install via pip   Note: It depends Pythonn 3.x</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Open Source Pymol in Windows by Conda</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-05-26-install-pymol-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 21:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-05-26-install-pymol-windows/</guid>
      <description>Since PyMOL 2.x released, there were no binary installer avaliable for Windows.
PyMOL Wiki provides the way to install open source PyMOL in Windows under Python 2.7.
This post provided the method to install PyMOL 2.x by conda (Anaconda or Minoconda) in Windows.
1. Install Conda Download Anaconda or Miniconda and install it.
 Note: Although PyMOL Wiki introduced PyMOL for Python 2.7 only, there are also pre-compiled PyMOL distribution for Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install conda compiler tools</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-05-23-install-conda-compiler-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 23:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2019-05-23-install-conda-compiler-tools/</guid>
      <description>Conda is quite convenient for non-root users to install softwares in Linux system. But sometimes there is no packages available in anaconda repository and we have to install these softwares from source. This post introduces the way to compile and install softwares from source, use the Kyoto Cabinet Perl module as an example.
1. Install compiler tools According to conda document, conda packages for Linux and macOS compilers is available since Anaconda 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BEAST Tips</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2018-11-16-beast-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 12:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2018-11-16-beast-tips/</guid>
      <description>BEAST (and BEAST 2, of course) is widely uesed for phylogenetic inference. But it is quite complicated. This post represents some useful tips while using BEAST.
1. Install beagle-lib Beagle-lib accelerates Bayesian and Maximun Likelihood phylogenetic software amazingly. Especially the beagle-lib v3.x improves 20-50% than version 2.x.
1.1 Compile beagle-lib without CUDA and OpenCL Although CUDA and OpenCL improves BEAST computing significantly, how to install beagle-lib without an Nvidia GPU card?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Nvidia CUDA in Debian Way</title>
      <link>https://omicx.cc/posts/2018-11-16-install-nvidia-cuda-in-debian-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 10:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omicx.cc/posts/2018-11-16-install-nvidia-cuda-in-debian-way/</guid>
      <description>For Debian stable/Stretch  Install NVidia driver in Linux server is always tedious and painful. Fortunatelly, Debian stable/Stretch provids ready-to-use NVidia drivers and CUDA toolkits. This post indicates the proper way to install up-to-date Nvidia driver and CUDA in Debian way.
1. Check repository source: For Debian stable/Stretch, the content of /etc/apt/sources.list file may looks like:
deb http://ftp.debian.org/debian/ stretch main contrib non-free 2. Remove previous installed NVidia drivers if necessary # apt-get remove --purge nvidia* 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
